<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Blog</title>
  <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2019-08-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/" />
  <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.4">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Testing Artefacts - V1.0.0-RC1</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190930_1-0-0-release.html</id>
    <updated>2019-08-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190930_1-0-0-release.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Nick Hamilton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Engineering Milestones - Testing Artefacts</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190909_testing_artefacts.html</id>
    <updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190909_testing_artefacts.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Nick Hamilton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a while, but the CDS Engineering team can now give an update on our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, in our team Nick Hamilton is joining us as interim Lead Engineer. Nick will draw upon his previous project delivery experiences in the FinTech/banking sector and his work as an engineer on earlier versions of the CDR Standards and InfoSec to provide technical guidance as we continue to produce artefacts to support the CDR ecosystem. We are also pleased to announce that we are adding an additional Senior Engineer to the team who will supplement Fei’s good work on the Engineering artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks the Engineering team has been working on consolidating the existing 10 git repositories into a single repo. This will make it easier for the community to navigate through the artefacts and to better understand their relationships. It will also enable better dependency and version management and will simplify our continuous integration. The cds-models, api-model and cds-conformance repos have been renamed to reference-test, and it can be found in the java-artefacts repo (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/ConsumerDataStandardsAustralia/java-artefacts/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ConsumerDataStandardsAustralia/java-artefacts/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next month, the Engineering team will be directing our efforts towards updating all our artefacts to align them with the latest versions of the CDS standards. We expect to release a 0.9.3 version first, and expect subsequent versions (0.9.4, 0.9.5 and 0.9.6) to all be released by 30th of September (subject to there being no significant rule updates that might cause major revisions to the Standards). An important component of our effort is updating the payload validation tool in the reference testing suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who are not familiar with our CDS testing suite, it has two components. The first component is a Payload Validation Tool, which checks the payload responses returned from Data Recipients. This tool accepts a JSON file as input (either locally or via a URL) and reports on the “correctness” of the structure of the data. It can be used to check the validity of endpoints defined in the Standards. The second tool – the Parameterised Test Tool - provides a way for testers to supply configuration files that specify custom input parameters to send to CDS endpoints and the response data that is expected to be returned. This tool utilises the open-source Serenity testing library (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.thucydides.info/#/whatisserenity&quot;&gt;http://www.thucydides.info/#/whatisserenity&lt;/a&gt;) to automatically make endpoint requests with the custom input parameters, and confirms that the responses are as expected. Currently it only supports the Product API, but work will begin on extending it to encompass Customer APIs in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the Engineering artefacts have been updated to the latest version of the Standards API, our engineering efforts will focus on implementing support for the InfoSec API into the artefacts. This is expected to be a major update that may take several months of engineering effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our planned deliverables are currently confined to use in a desktop sandbox, we would welcome any contributions from the community that might extend them to support a cloud-based environment. We have created simple licensing agreements to ensure any individual or corporate contributions are recognised and these Harmony-based agreements will be published on the engineering website in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if there are any questions in regards to our artefacts, please feel free to contact the Engineering team, or raise a git issue if you find a bug or want to suggest a feature enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to working with you as we head toward implementing the CDS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Stuart’s Farewell</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190730_stuart_farewell.html</id>
    <updated>2019-07-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190730_stuart_farewell.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Louis Taborda</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most of the CDR community already are aware that Stuart Low has left Data61 to pursue other interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thank Stu for his passionate contribution to the CDS discussions and particularly for his work developing the related engineering outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The return of Perlboy is already evident and we look forward to his constructive involvement to help make the CDR regime a success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best going forward, Stu!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">0.9.3 Artefacts Updated</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190719_0.9.3_artefacts_updated.html</id>
    <updated>2019-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190719_0.9.3_artefacts_updated.html" />
    <author>
      <name>fyang1024</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have updated some 0.9.3 artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updates are:&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">0.9.3 Documentation Updated</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190701_0.9.3_documentation_updated.html</id>
    <updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190701_0.9.3_documentation_updated.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little while but I have now published updated documentation for the 0.9.3 artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition I’ve uploaded and linked the &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;engineering_workshops/round2/index.html#workshop-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Workshop Round 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; material.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #6 Started</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190603_sprint6_started.html</id>
    <updated>2019-06-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190603_sprint6_started.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few weeks since I last sent an update so I thought it was prudent but I will keep it short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Sprint 4 and Sprint 5 focused on internal code review with significant tweaks around ensuring the code developed for the artefacts had a high quality baseline. Following the result in Canberra, it is important that we realigned our work with the intended CDR delivery schedule so that we can ensure that the tools delivered are the most useful relative to the expectations of the government for Data Holder’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently we are now focused on the July 1 target timeline for Product Reference Data and functionally demonstrating all of the components to make this a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #3 Engineering Video Update</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190505_video_update.html</id>
    <updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-05-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190505_video_update.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As promised I have now published a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zOItBfCU-cM&quot;&gt;video on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; giving a quick demonstration of the artefacts as they stand right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback always welcome and we look forward to providing further updates soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #3 Complete</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190503_sprint3_complete.html</id>
    <updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-05-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190503_sprint3_complete.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s always great when after effort in many different areas you have something that pays off. Looking back on the past 4-6 weeks and what we’ve got done we are proud of where we have got so far. It’s also a time to take note and improve on what has been developed (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we made available a number of CDS Codegen generated artefacts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java Client Library available on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://oss.sonatype.org/#nexus-search;quick~cds-client-java&quot;&gt;Sonatype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #2 Closed</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190418_sprint2_closed.html</id>
    <updated>2019-04-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-04-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190418_sprint2_closed.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once again it has been a pretty big fortnight as we got deep into taking our Models built in &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint1.html#sprint-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and initiating the production of Codegen. While we haven’t quite got to where we wanted to be by now we are pretty happy with the progress and have now made available Product API focused samples for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/ConsumerDataStandardsAustralia/cds-codegen/tree/cds-artefact-generator/support/samples/cds-client-java&quot;&gt;Client&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/ConsumerDataStandardsAustralia/cds-codegen/tree/cds-artefact-generator/support/samples/cds-stubs-java-spring&quot;&gt;Server Stubs (using Spring)&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/ConsumerDataStandardsAustralia/cds-codegen/tree/cds-artefact-generator/support/samples/cds-holder-java-spring&quot;&gt;Model Holder&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the adventurous these are available directly from source now and we have put in a task on &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint3.html#sprint-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to publish Docker containers and produce a quick showcase video. Within &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint3.html#sprint-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we will now use these samples as input templates into the ongoing code generation work currently occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Easter upon us we completed a retrospective and the final report is available in the &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint2.html#sprint-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documentation. All up there has now been 30,000 (!!) lines of additional code added to our repositories in &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint2.html#sprint-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; alone and we ticked over on 300+ commits across our repositories this sprint. We suspect this will only accelerate further as we progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #1 Completed</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190405_sprint1_completed.html</id>
    <updated>2019-04-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-04-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190405_sprint1_completed.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well it has been a pretty full on fortnight as we did our first major sprint but we are happy to report that after quite a few long days we achieved our major target of defining the Standards in Java Models and generating a swagger specification that is mostly identical to the Standards swagger. We completed a retrospective and the final report is available in the &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint1.html#sprint-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documentation, we will look to finalise &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;sprints/sprint2.html#sprint-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;std std-ref&quot;&gt;Sprint #2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; planning on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Feedback Requests Round #1</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190328_feedback_round1.html</id>
    <updated>2019-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190328_feedback_round1.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As communicated previously we have been working towards an initial set of feedback requests. The first two of these are now published and open for comment (see title links) on the GitHub engineering issues list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intention will be to have these formally submitted as Decision Proposals following an initial feedback period. Our target completion duration for feedback is 14 days but we are open to extensions when “it makes sense”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Sprint #0 Completed</title>
    <id>https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190322_sprint0_completed.html</id>
    <updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://consumerdatastandardsaustralia.github.io/engineering/updates/20190322_sprint0_completed.html" />
    <author>
      <name>Stuart Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Engineering Working Group has had a busy fortnight with extensive planning, definition of goals and deliverables along with more lower level task generation for Sprints #1 to #3. In addition Fei Yang joined the team providing additional engineering capability.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
